PROFILE

Software engineer with 7 years of experience in backend software development mainly for **FinTech** startups. Preferred programming language is **Golang**. Highly professional, focused on delivering product in short time without any supervision. Was a technical **leader** and has leadership experience and skills. Developed and launched core prime brokerage platform which brought 100% of Bequant revenue. Built and launched Zodia Markets "Request for quote" system which brought first profit to the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal Engineer

Dec 2022 - ...

Zodia Markets by Standard Chartered and OSL, Dubai, UAE

The first digital asset brokerage and exchange backed by a leading international bank - https://zodiamarkets.com.

• Aiming to run own crypto exchange together with DevOps and Support Engineers migrated and reconfigured whole infrastructure and codebase bought from OSL Exchange. This exchange wasn't production ready so I sanitized it Java and Kotlin codebase from bugs and ineffective code, created several Python scripts for easy infrastructure management, built all the Docker images and we successfully ran our own exchange. Wrote unit and integrations tests for exchange functionality.

As RnD engineer responsible for every 3-rd party integration:

- Developed in Golang and integrated transaction monitoring system using Solidus Halo to satisfy regulations about preventing harmful transactions.
- For proper risks accounting built in Golang portfolio data management and trades dropcopy system through Elwood Platform.
- Developed in Golang universal FIX gateway for easy client access to any trading and market data bank systems.

Technical Lead

Bequant, Limassol, Cyprus

Mar 2021 - Nov 2022

Broker specializes in principal trading, comprehensive OTC trading, custody, and borrowing/lending services tailored for institutional and professional investors - https://bequant.pro.

• Led the team of 6 backend developers. Interviewed team member candidates, guided team through technical issues and challenges, made system design decisions, supervised junior members, wrote technical documentation, implemented crucial core system elements in Golang.

Software Engineer

Apr 2020 - Mar 2021

Bequant, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

• For the purpose of creation own prime brokerage platform implemented in Golang core high loaded service for async fetching data from crypto exchanges using cursor, rate limiter, retrier, sorting, batching etc. algorithms. Implemented async service for 'over the counter' withdrawals processing, order creating processing etc.

Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Nov 2020

Epam Systems, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

US company that specializes in software engineering services - https://www.epam.com. As outsource engineer I worked for two projects:

- Aspiration bank https://www.aspiration.com: maintenance and development of bank backend platform in Golang (forbidden disclosure).
- SLB https://www.slb.com development of continental shelf visualization backend platform in Golang (forbidden disclosure).

Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2019 – Jun 2020

$Diacare\text{-}soft\ (later-Sporra),\ Saint\text{-}Petersburg,\ Russia$

Clinic, developer of IT solutions in the field of medicine and healthcare - https://sporra.ru.

• Developed Golang microservices in the direction of migration of a legacy monolithic telemedicine application (staffing control, symptoms analysis, patient recommendation generation, fast messages exchange, face recognition) to microservice architecture.

Mobile Backend Developer

Aug 2018 – Oct 2018

IQOption, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Online crypto trading company - https://iq-option.com.

• Developed Golang backend of Treasure Hunt - shooter for IOS with additional reality features.

Golang Developer

Mar 2018 – Aug 2018

Atlant, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

Real estate blockchain platform – https://atlant.io.

• Developed in Golang decentralized blockchain platform that solves two of the most pertinent problems in real estate: Tokenized Ownership and global P2P Rentals.

Web-Developer Jun 2017 – Mar 2018

Service007, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

B2B and B2C flights, trains, and hotels aggregator.

• Developed in Python and supported aggregator service for searching, booking, and buying air tickets, for hotel searching and reservation.

SKILLS

English C1, Docker, Git, Golang, Java, Kotlin, NodeJS, Python, Swagger, OpenAPI, WebSocket, FIX, MySQL, Kafka, Redis, Prometheus, AWS, AMQ, PostgreSQL, Nats, Clickhouse, TypeScript, Protobuf, Circle-ci, RabbitMQ, AWS, Rancher, GCP, Azure, MongoDB, InfluxDB, MQTT, BadgerDB, IPFS, Go-Ethereum, Solidity, Gitlab, Highload.

SIDE ACTIVITIES

• Python mentor at Solvery.io (May 2020 – Oct 2021). One successful case of mentee getting Epam Systems internship.

EDUCATION

• Saint-Petersburg State University of Aerospace Instrumentation, Specialist (2005-2010)